Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
我是Katherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程。
That's right.
没错。
Today, we are getting a tattoo.
今天，我们要去纹身。
Okay, so a tattoo is a picture that you get on your body and it lasts forever.
好的，纹身就是你在身上弄的图案，而且它会永久保留。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to get a tattoo.
所以我们要去纹身。
We're going to talk about this very popular form of art on your skin.
我们要聊聊这种非常流行的皮肤艺术形式。
And so let's start with the dialogue.
那么，我们先从对话开始吧。
Let's listen to it and we'll be back in a bit.
我们来听一下，一会儿再回来。
I have made up my mind.
我已经下定决心了。
I'm getting a tattoo.
我要去纹身。
Really?
真的吗？
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Yeah, why not?
是啊，为什么不呢？
They're trendy and look great.
它们很时髦，看起来也很棒。
I want to get a dragon on my arm or maybe a tiger on my back.
我想在胳膊上纹条龙，或者在后背纹只老虎。
Yeah, but it's something that you'll have forever.
是啊，但这是会伴随你一辈子的东西。
They use indelible ink that can only be removed with laser treatment.
他们用的是不可擦除的墨水，只能用激光治疗去除。
On top of all of that, I've heard it hurts a lot.
除此之外，我听说纹身很疼。
Really?
真的吗？
Of course.
当然。
They use this machine with a needle that pokes your skin and inserts the ink.
他们用一种带针的机器，刺入你的皮肤并注入墨水。
Oh, I didn't know that.
哦，我不知道这个。
I thought they just painted on your skin or something.
我以为他们只是在你皮肤上画画之类的。
I think you should reconsider and do some more research about tattoos.
我觉得你应该重新考虑一下，再多了解了解纹身。
Also, find out where the nearest tattoo parlor is and make sure that you sterilize needles
另外，找找最近的纹身店，确保他们消毒针头，
and the place is hygienic.
而且环境是卫生的。
Maybe I should just get a tongue piercing.
也许我该去打个舌钉。
Ew.
呃。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now, let's take a look at five key words that we've picked out for you on Language
现在，让我们来看看我们在“语言要点”中为你挑选的五个关键词。
Takeaway.
语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
So the first phrase that we have here on Language Takeaway is indelible ink.
所以我们在“语言要点”中的第一个短语是“不可擦除的墨水”。
That's right.
没错。
When you get a tattoo, they draw it on your skin with indelible ink.
当你纹身时，他们用不可擦除的墨水在你皮肤上画图案。
Okay, well, ink is what you find in a pen.
好的，墨水就是你笔里的东西。
So when you write, you write with ink.
所以写字时，你用墨水写。
And this is something that you can also paint with.
而且你也可以用它来画画。
But in this case, we're talking about indelible ink.
但在这里，我们说的是不可擦除的墨水。
So that means it's going to be permanent in your skin.
这意味着它会永久留在你的皮肤里。
So something that is indelible means that you cannot delete or erase.
所以不可擦除的东西意味着你不能删除或擦掉。
That's right.
没错。
You can't take it away.
你无法去除它。
Okay, indelible ink.
好的，不可擦除的墨水。
Or sometimes people just say permanent ink.
或者有时人们直接说永久墨水。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So obviously, if you get a tattoo with indelible ink, if you want to get it removed, now you
所以很明显，如果你用不可擦除的墨水纹身，想去除的话，现在可以用激光治疗。
can with laser treatment.
可以用激光治疗。
Okay, so laser treatment uses this very strong light to burn the ink out of your skin.
好的，激光治疗用这种强光把墨水从皮肤里烧掉。
And it is something that you actually have to go and do many, many times to get the tattoo
而且实际上你需要去很多次才能把纹身去除。
removed.
才能去除纹身。
I've also heard that it's very painful.
我还听说那非常疼。
Yeah, I've heard that.
是啊，我也听说过。
It hurts a lot, more than getting the tattoo.
很疼，比纹身还疼。
Right.
对。
So laser removal or laser treatment is something that you do when you want to take a tattoo
所以激光去除或激光治疗是你想从身上去掉纹身时做的事情。
off your body.
从身上去掉纹身。
I think they also use laser treatment to remove, maybe you have stains on your skin, like from
我觉得激光治疗也用来去除，比如你皮肤上的斑点，像太阳晒的，甚至脱毛，我听说过。
the sun, or even to remove hair, I heard.
我听说过。
Yeah, laser hair removal is something that many people do to take away some of the hair
是啊，激光脱毛是很多人用来去除身上不想要的毛发的方法。
on their bodies that they don't like.
去除身上不想要的毛发。
Okay.
好的。
So obviously, because tattoos are forever, this friend is asking this other person to
所以很明显，因为纹身是永久的，这个朋友在让另一个人重新考虑，再多了解了解纹身。
reconsider and do some more research about tattoos.
再多了解了解纹身。
Well, to consider something means to think about it.
嗯，“考虑”某事就是思考它。
So to reconsider means to think about it again.
所以“重新考虑”就是再次思考。
Right.
对。
So if you're going to make a big decision, you should reconsider what you're going to
所以如果你要做一个重大决定，你应该重新考虑你要做什么。
do.
你要做什么。
For example, I really want to have a hamburger for dinner, but maybe I should reconsider
比如，我真的很想晚餐吃汉堡，但也许我应该重新考虑，因为汉堡不太健康。
because hamburgers aren't very healthy.
因为汉堡不太健康。
Maybe I should decide on a salad or something.
也许我应该决定吃沙拉之类的。
Very good.
很好。
Okay.
好的。
So to reconsider.
所以是“重新考虑”。
Now, obviously, when we have a tattoo done, when we get a tattoo, they use this little
现在，很明显，当我们纹身时，他们用这个小东西。
machine that has a needle inside and it vibrates very, very fast and it kind of injects the
这种机器里面有一根针，它振动得非常非常快，有点像把墨水注射进去。
ink.
墨水。
So the friend tells this person to make sure that when they use this machine, they use
所以朋友告诉这个人，要确保在使用这种机器时，使用消毒过的针头。
sterilized needles.
消毒过的针头。
Okay.
好的。
So needles are those very small little things that go into your skin.
所以针头就是那些进入你皮肤的小东西。
They hurt.
它们很疼。
When you get a shot, the doctor will use a needle as well.
当你打针时，医生也会用针头。
But a sterilized needle is a needle that is clean.
但消毒过的针头是干净的针头。
So something that is sterilized means clean.
所以消毒过的东西意味着干净。
That's right.
没错。
But it's clean for medical use.
但它是用于医疗用途的干净。
That means that maybe someone used alcohol or even fire to clean something.
这意味着可能有人用酒精甚至火来清洁东西。
Okay.
好的。
So as you said, it needs to go through a process to be sterilized.
所以就像你说的，它需要经过一个过程才能消毒。
Like if you wash your dishes, they're not sterilized.
比如你洗碗，它们不是消毒过的。
No.
不是。
But if you are getting surgery on your body, the doctor is going to cut you open.
但如果你要做身体手术，医生会切开你的身体。
He will use sterilized tools.
他会用消毒过的工具。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And moving on to our last word, very much related to sterilized needles.
然后说到我们最后一个词，和消毒过的针头非常相关。
We're talking about something that is hygienic, to make sure that everything is hygienic when
我们在谈论卫生的东西，确保当你纹身时一切都卫生。
you get a tattoo done.
纹身。
Okay.
好的。
Well, something that is hygienic is clean.
嗯，卫生的东西就是干净的。
So if you have a baby, you want to make sure that the room that the baby is in is very
所以如果你有宝宝，你要确保宝宝所在的房间非常卫生。
hygienic.
卫生。
So you clean it very often.
所以你经常清洁它。
Maybe you use some sterilizer to clean the different surfaces and things like that, because
也许你用一些消毒剂来清洁不同的表面之类的东西，因为宝宝容易生病。
babies can get sick easily.
容易生病。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So we've taken a look at five key words there.
所以我们看了五个关键词。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again?
我们为什么不重新听一遍我们的对话呢？
We can review what we've just learned and we'll be back in a little bit with Fluency Builder.
我们可以复习刚学的内容，稍后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
I have made up my mind.
我已经下定决心了。
I'm getting a tattoo.
我要去纹身。
Really?
真的吗？
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Why not?
为什么不呢？
They're trendy and look great.
它们很时尚，看起来很棒。
I want to get a dragon on my arm or maybe a tiger on my back.
我想在胳膊上纹一条龙，或者背上纹一只老虎。
Yeah, but it's something that you'll have forever.
是啊，但这是你永远会有的东西。
They use indelible ink that can only be removed with laser treatment.
他们用不可擦除的墨水，只能用激光治疗去除。
On top of all of that, I've heard it hurts a lot.
除此之外，我听说很疼。
Really?
真的吗？
Of course.
当然。
They use this machine with a needle that pokes your skin and inserts the ink.
他们用这种带针的机器刺你的皮肤，注入墨水。
Oh, I didn't know that.
哦，我不知道。
I thought they just painted on your skin or something.
我以为他们只是在你皮肤上画或者类似的东西。
I think you should reconsider and do some more research about tattoos.
我觉得你应该重新考虑，多做一些关于纹身的研究。
Also, find out where the nearest tattoo parlor is and make sure that you sterilize needles
另外，找找最近的纹身店，确保他们消毒针头，而且地方卫生。
and the place is hygienic.
卫生。
Maybe I should just get a tongue piercing.
也许我应该只打个舌钉。
Ew.
呃。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看流利度训练中的一些短语。
We only have three phrases today, but the first one is a phrase you'll hear very, very
我们今天只有三个短语，但第一个是你在英语中会经常听到的短语。
often in English.
经常听到。
It's I've made up my mind.
就是“我已经下定决心了”。
That's right.
没错。
The dialogue starts by saying I've made up my mind.
对话开头说“我已经下定决心了”。
I am getting a tattoo.
我要去纹身。
So what does it mean if you have made up your mind?
那么如果你已经下定决心了，是什么意思呢？
Well, it means that you have decided something.
嗯，意思是你已经决定了某件事。
I have decided to do something.
我已经决定做某件事了。
And the present tense of this phrase is to make up someone's mind.
这个短语的现在时是“让某人下定决心”。
So I make up my mind, you make up your mind, he makes up his mind.
所以我下定决心，你下定决心，他下定决心。
Okay, so if you're choosing something or making a decision, when you finally make that decision,
好的，所以如果你在选择某物或做决定，当你最终做出那个决定时，就意味着你已经下定决心了。
that means that you have made up your mind.
下定决心了。
Maybe we're shopping, Marco, and you're thinking, well, do I want this or do I want that?
也许我们在购物，Marco，你在想，嗯，我要这个还是那个？
Well, I'll say, come on, Marco, make up your mind.
嗯，我会说，快点，Marco，下定决心吧。
That's right.
没错。
It means just pick one.
意思就是选一个。
Just decide.
就决定吧。
Decide.
决定。
Very good.
非常好。
That's a very common phrase to make up your mind, to make a decision.
这是一个很常见的短语，意思是“下定决心”或“做决定”。
And well, as we continued on with the dialogue, the friend was saying how the tattoos are
嗯，随着对话的继续，朋友在说纹身是
forever and if you want to get it removed, you need to use laser treatment and ends this
永久的，如果你想去除它，需要用激光治疗，最后
part by saying on top of all that, I have heard it hurts a lot.
这部分以“最重要的是，我听说它很疼”结束。
On top of all that.
最重要的是。
This means and even more.
这表示“而且还有更多”。
So basically when you're trying to give reasons for something, maybe reasons for doing something
所以基本上，当你试图为某事找理由时，可能是做某事的理由
or reasons for not doing something, you give your reasons and at the end you say and on
或不做的理由，你列出理由，最后说“而且
top of all that.
最重要的是”。
So in addition or even more than that, this is the case.
所以除此之外或甚至更多，情况就是这样。
Right.
对。
So maybe we're talking about a car and you say, well, that car is not very reliable.
所以也许我们在谈论一辆车，你说，嗯，那辆车不太可靠。
It uses a lot of fuel.
它很耗油。
It's very uncomfortable inside.
里面很不舒服。
And on top of that, it's expensive.
而且最重要的是，它很贵。
And on top of all that, it's ugly.
而且最重要的是，它很丑。
That's right.
没错。
So you're kind of listing things and you're telling the person why you think something
所以你是在列举事情，告诉对方你为什么认为某事
is good or bad and then you end it by giving a final reason.
好或坏，然后最后给出一个最终理由。
And on top of that.
而且最重要的是。
Exactly.
正是。
All right.
好了。
And our last phrase, it's actually interesting because the place where you go and get a tattoo
我们最后一个短语，其实挺有趣的，因为你去纹身的地方
is called a tattoo parlor.
叫做“纹身店”。
Okay.
好的。
It's a parlor.
它叫“店”。
Now, this is interesting because you might think that you would say a tattoo shop, but
这很有趣，因为你可能会以为会说“纹身商店”，但
we don't say this.
我们不这么说。
So think about a beauty salon or beauty parlor.
所以想想美容院或美容店。
A parlor is a shop where we get our appearance changed.
“店”是一个改变我们外貌的店铺。
In this case, a tattoo parlor is a special shop where you can get a tattoo or in the
在这种情况下，纹身店是一个特殊的店铺，你可以去纹身，或者
case of this person, maybe get your ears pierced or your tongue pierced or your nose pierced.
像这个人一样，也许去打耳洞、舌钉或鼻钉。
So a tattoo parlor is a place to go for that.
所以纹身店就是去那里的地方。
All right.
好了。
So a lot of phrases there.
所以有很多短语。
Let's review everything one last time and we'll be back to talk some more.
让我们最后复习一遍，然后回来再聊更多。
I have made up my mind.
我已经下定决心了。
I'm getting a tattoo.
我要去纹身。
Really?
真的吗？
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Why not?
为什么不呢？
They're trendy and look great.
它们很时尚，看起来很棒。
I want to get a dragon on my arm or maybe a tiger on my back.
我想在胳膊上纹条龙，或者背上纹只老虎。
Yeah, but it's something that you'll have forever.
是啊，但这是你永远会有的东西。
They use indelible ink that can only be removed with laser treatment.
他们用的是不可擦除的墨水，只能用激光治疗去除。
On top of all of that, I've heard it hurts a lot.
最重要的是，我听说它很疼。
Really?
真的吗？
Of course.
当然。
They use this machine with a needle that pokes your skin and inserts the ink.
他们用那种带针的机器，刺入你的皮肤并注入墨水。
Oh, I didn't know that.
哦，我不知道。
I thought they just painted on your skin or something.
我以为他们只是在你皮肤上画之类的。
I think you should reconsider and do some more research about tattoos.
我觉得你应该重新考虑，多研究一下纹身。
Also, find out where the nearest tattoo parlor is and make sure that you sterilize needles
另外，找找最近的纹身店在哪里，确保针头消毒
and the place is hygienic.
而且地方卫生。
Maybe I should just get a tongue piercing.
也许我应该只打个舌钉。
Ew.
呃。
So talking about tattoos and also piercings, a very popular thing nowadays, especially
所以说到纹身和穿孔，现在很流行，尤其是
we didn't touch on the piercing aspect of the dialogue, to get your ears pierced or
我们没怎么涉及对话中的穿孔部分，打耳洞或
to get your tongue pierced means that you're going to create a hole in your tongue so you
打舌钉意味着你要在舌头上开个洞，这样
can put a ring or something in it.
就能放个环之类的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So many women have their ears pierced.
很多女性都打了耳洞。
This means that they can wear earrings and these are small holes in the bottom of your
这意味着她们可以戴耳环，这些是耳朵底部的小洞。
ear.
耳朵。
But a lot of people nowadays like to get their nose pierced, so a hole in the side of the
但现在很多人喜欢打鼻钉，也就是鼻子侧面的洞，
nose or their tongues pierced.
或者打舌钉。
That's right.
没错。
You see people now get eyebrows pierced, their lips pierced, even below the lip, like I don't
你会看到人们现在打眉钉、唇钉，甚至嘴唇下面，比如我不知道，
know, near the chin, between the chin and the lip, they get this thing through it.
靠近下巴，在下巴和嘴唇之间，他们穿个东西过去。
It's very interesting.
这很有趣。
Yeah.
是的。
Also, I've seen belly buttons.
还有，我见过肚脐。
Belly buttons get pierced.
肚脐也会被打孔。
Like on your stomach.
就像在肚子上。
That's right.
没错。
And tattoos as well.
还有纹身。
Tattoos are so popular now.
纹身现在很流行。
People get tattoos, arms, legs, your neck, face, everywhere now.
人们纹身，胳膊、腿、脖子、脸，到处都有。
That's right.
没错。
And there are special names for these in English.
在英语中，这些还有专门的名称。
For example, if you have a very big tattoo in your arm from your shoulder to your elbow,
比如，如果你胳膊上有一个很大的纹身，从肩膀一直到手肘，
that's called a sleeve tattoo because it looks like a permanent sleeve.
那就叫做“袖套纹身”，因为它看起来像一只永久的袖子。
That's right.
没错。
And actually, women get tattoos also, but for cosmetic reasons.
实际上，女性也会纹身，但更多是出于美容目的。
Many women get their eyebrows tattooed.
很多女性会纹眉毛。
Yeah, I've seen this.
嗯，我见过这个。
So, some women like to get these tattoos that look like makeup.
所以，有些女性喜欢纹这种看起来像化妆的纹身。
So maybe if you want your nice eyebrows all the time, you get these eyebrow tattoos or
比如，如果你想一直拥有漂亮的眉毛，就可以纹眉毛，或者
if you want some dark lines under your eyes, like eyeliner, then you get the eyeliner tattoo.
如果你想要眼睛下面有深色线条，像眼线一样，那就纹眼线。
Also, I've seen the lips, lip liner tattoo.
我还见过嘴唇的唇线纹身。
They do it around the lips to make it seem like you consistently have lip liner.
他们在嘴唇周围纹，让你看起来一直有唇线。
Interesting.
有意思。
Well, I don't know if I do that because some days you just don't want to wear makeup.
嗯，我不知道我会不会这么做，因为有些日子你根本不想化妆。
That's right.
没错。
But actually, tattoos in many cultures are frowned upon.
但实际上，纹身在很多文化中是不被认可的。
I know that until very recently in Japanese culture, tattoos were illegal because they
我知道直到最近，在日本文化中，纹身还是非法的，因为它们
were sent to the Yakuza.
与黑帮有关联。
And in Jewish culture, you're not allowed to have a tattoo on your body.
而在犹太文化中，你身上不允许有纹身。
And so, if you die with a tattoo, you cannot go to a Jewish graveyard.
所以，如果你带着纹身去世，就不能葬在犹太墓地。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
I've also heard that in many countries, some positions, some job positions, you cannot
我还听说在很多国家，有些职位、有些工作岗位，你
obtain if you have a tattoo.
如果有纹身就无法获得。
Wow, Saul.
哇，索尔。
It's very interesting.
这很有意思。
I don't know why that would influence it.
我不知道为什么这会影响工作。
I think it's definitely culture to culture because it's very popular in America right
我觉得这绝对因文化而异，因为在美国，现在纹身
now to have tattoos.
非常流行。
But in China and Japan and East Asia, they're definitely frowned upon.
但在中国、日本和东亚，纹身肯定是不被认可的。
Even for example, in the armed forces in the United States, it's very popular for them
比如，在美国军队里，他们很流行纹
to have an American flag or something.
美国国旗之类的东西。
You see it all the time in movies.
你在电影里经常看到。
But in other countries, you cannot join the armed forces if you have a tattoo.
但在其他国家，如果你有纹身，就不能参军。
Interesting.
有意思。
Well, let us know.
嗯，告诉我们吧。
Is having a tattoo okay in your culture or do people tend to think that it's a bad thing?
在你们的文化中，纹身是可以接受的吗？还是人们倾向于认为这是不好的事？
Or maybe you have a tattoo.
或者也许你就有纹身。
Do you have a tattoo or a piercing in your nose or your lip or your tongue?
你有纹身吗？或者鼻子、嘴唇、舌头上打孔？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right.
好了。
Bye, guys.
再见，各位。
Thanks a lot.
非常感谢。